天啊
Oh man.
哇哦
Wow.
我打小之后就再没回来过
I haven't been here since I was a little kid.
我还以为你在这长大的
I thought you grew up here.
就前面拐角那一带
Like round the corner.
我就是在那个台阶上把牙磕掉的
I knocked my tooth out on that step.
脑子都磕坏了
Got me brain damaged.
虽然比不上纽约 但这是咱俩的小窝
It's not New York, but... it's ours.
我觉得以后会很快活 对吧?
I think it's gonna be pretty sick, no?
嗯?
Yeah?
-我把架子鼓运过来成不?-想都别想
- I could send for my drum kit? - No way.
不行?
No?
我叔叔以前爱囤东西 我没想到这儿…
My uncle was a hoarder. I didn't realise how much...
原来这么宽敞
space there was in here.
挺清净啊
It's peaceful.
在这地方录专辑再舒服不过了
I can just record an album out here so easily.
-格蕾丝 -干嘛?
- Gracie! - What?
我找到个书房
I found an office!
哦
Oh.
你以后可以在这写你那部伟大的美国小说了
You can write your Great American Novel up here.
哇
Whoa!
怎么了?
What?
呃…
Um...
没事就几只老鼠
It's alright. It's just a little rat situation.
咱们该养只猫了
We should get a cat.
你可以从早写到晚 安静得只剩鸟叫
You can write all day, every day. Nothing but the birds singing.
他怎么死的?
How did he die?
呃…
Um...
我不知道
I don't know.
就这了
Here we are.
得先找把扫帚
We need a broom.
嘿嘿嘿
Hey, hey, hey.
嘿
Hey.
来吧 我们再扭一曲
Came on, let's twist again
嘿 你妈妈呢?
Hey! Where's your mommy?
小南瓜 你妈呢?
Pumpkin, where's your mommy?
哦 糟咯
Oh, no!
妈妈去哪了?
Where's Mommy?
天啊
Oh, God.
格蕾丝
Grace.
我妈想顺道过来一趟
Mom wanted to stop by.
哦?
Oh?
我跟她说了没大 就只是咱俩自己的事
I told her it wasn't a big deal. It's like a "us" thing.
反正也就待六个月吧 所以…
And it's just for six months, anyway, so...
嗯
Mm-hmm.
我就是有点过意不去
I just feel kind of bad,
我觉得她只是想有人陪
'cause I think she just wants the company.
我不介意她来
I don't mind her coming.
真怪她好像不知道一个人怎么过了
It's weird. It's like she doesn't know how to function any more.
做饭还按两人份 她跟你说过吗?
She's still cooking for two people. Did she tell you that?
太甜了
It's too sweet.
是吗?我觉得挺好啊
Yeah? No, it's nice.
他喜欢甜的
He liked it.
真正当妈的会烤个蛋糕
A real mom would have baked a cake.
再来一瓶?
Want another one?
怎么他妈的这么热?
Why is it so fuckin' hot?
“怎么他妈的这么热?”
"Why is it so fuckin' hot?"
这里一直这么热
It's always hot.
孩子睡了
Boy's asleep.
嗯
Mm-hmm.
你要看吗?
You wanna look?
格蕾丝 你怎么能对星星这么无动于衷?
How can you not give a shit about the stars, Grace?
看着它们 我觉得自己啥也不是
Well, they make me feel like nothing.
我倒喜欢这种成为浩瀚宇宙一份子的感觉
I like they make me feel like I'm part of something bigger.
你就喜欢觉得自己啥也不是?
You like to feel like nothing?
不
No.
你知道外面有多少个宇宙吗?
You know how many universes there are out there?
在别的宇宙里我们在干嘛 还会在一起吗?
What are we doing in the different universe? Are we together?
当然
Sure we are.
那我是不是搖滾女明星?
Am I a rock star?
嗯…
Hmm...
在别的宇宙里你会唱歌吗?
Can you sing in a different universe?
嘿
Hey.
会 我敢肯定你是
Yeah, I'm sure you're a rock star.
那我们会不会做爱?
Do we fuck?
会
Uh-huh.
一直做?
All the time?
你说啥?
Hey, what?
我们 到底 会不会做爱?
Do. We. Fuck?
跟兔子一样频繁
Like rabbits.
你听见孩子声音了吗?
Do you hear him?
没听见
No.
他在哭呢 你听
He's crying. Listen.
格蕾丝 这儿一点声音都没有
Grace, it's totally silent.
我把你说烦了?
Am I boring you?
跟你无关 宇宙的问题
Not you. The universe.
谁在乎啊?
Who gives a shit?
摸起来像女孩吗?
Does it feel like a girl?
女孩摸起来什么感觉?
What does a girl feel like?
要是右边动得多点
If it moves more on the right,
那你多半怀的是男孩
then you're probably having a boy.
你不想提前知道吗?
You didn't wanna know?
不想
Mm-mm.
格蕾丝 我…
Grace, I...
我当年也没提前去查自己怀的是啥
I didn't find out what I was having either.
我觉得那样挺好的
I think that's nice.
你不去查是因为你想要个女儿
You didn't find out 'cause you wanted a girl.
天啊 他又忘了喝
Oh, gosh. He forgets to drink.
哈利 你得喝一杯
Harry, you gotta have a drink.
不 我没有 我只是想要个孩子 谁在肚子里我都要
No, I didn't, I wanted a baby. I wanted whoever was in there.
是吗 然后你生下了杰克森?
Yeah? And you got Jackson?
真不走运
Unlucky.
我听到了 珍姨
I heard that, Auntie Jen.
格蕾丝 没胃口吗?
Are you off your food, Grace?
-别管她 -你刚才都没吃东西
- Leave her alone. - You didn't eat.
怀孕会让胃口变小
Being pregnant makes your stomach shrink.
那是胡扯
That's bullshit.
那小家伙每天每分钟都在吸你的营养
It's sucking on you every minute of the day.
然后你就会饿坏 我那时候怎么吃都吃不够
Then you'll be famished. I couldn't get enough in me.
你这毛病一直没改 是吧?
That never went away, did it?
你倒会说 你自己又有什么借口?
You can talk. What's your excuse?
自己从没生过 吃起来像刚生了三胞胎似的
Never had a baby but always ate as though you'd just had triplets.
你知道吗 格蕾丝 要是你生的是个爱哭鬼…
You know, Grace, if you get a screamer...
她不会生爱哭鬼的
She's not gonna get a screamer.
杰克森小时候就是个爱哭鬼
Jackson was a screamer.
-胡说 -杰克森小时候可乖了
- That's a lie! - Jackson was a sweetheart.
重点是 真遇上那种 就让孩子自己哭去
The point is, if you do, let the baby cry.
你就暂时离开一下 别把自己弄得又累又紧绷
Just walk away from it. Don't let yourself get tired, stressed.
这么说太吓人了
That's a horrible thing to say.
简直是慢性折磨
Slow fuckin' death.
你要是状态不好 对谁都不好 尤其是对孩子
If you're not at your best, it's no good for anyone, especially the baby.
而且孩子哭不代表他难受
And a crying baby doesn't mean it's in pain.
那是他们唯一和大人的交流方式
It's the only way they have of communicating.
不 才不是这样
No, it's not.
人家爱说那种屁话 是因为想着能心安理得丢下孩子
People say that shit because they wanna walk away from their kid.
反正我整天就只是在照顾哈利
Anyway, all I do is take care of Harry.
- 勉强算吧 - 要是你需要我的话…
- Barely. - If you need me...
-她不用 -我们走几步就到
- She doesn't. - ...we're just a walk away.
爸 你在这干嘛 想看灰熊队比赛吗?
What you doing in here, Pop? Wanna watch the Grizzlies?
想拆礼物吗?儿
Wanna open some of those presents?
谁的礼物?
Whose presents?
给宝宝的
For the baby.
不用 我得把这几双鞋先理清楚
No, I gotta sort out these shoes.
-好吧 -这双鞋拿错了
- Okay. - They're the wrong ones.
我看着挺好
They look good to me.
-妈你吃饱了吗?-宝贝 我吃撑了
- You had enough to eat, Mom? - Honey, I'm stuffed.
帮你爸倒点喝的好吗?
Would you get your dad something to drink, please?
给 老爸
Here you go, Pop.
别再给我吃派了
No more pie.
唉 我也是吃撑了
Well, I'm stuffed.
就是停不下嘴 每逢过节都这样
Can't stop eating. It's the same every holiday.
你能吃 你一直都很瘦
Well, you can do it. You've always been skinny.
格蕾丝就喜欢我瘦点 对吧 宝贝?
Grace likes me lean. Don't you, baby?
你可以一月份再饿回来
You can starve in January.
你们都在干嘛 你们怎么在这儿?
What are y'all doing? Why are y'all here?
这是弗兰克的房子
This is Frank's house.
这是他的房子
It's his house.
哈利 这里现在是格蕾丝和杰克森的…
Harry, this is Grace and Jackson's--
不 这是我弟的房子
No, this is my brother's house.
亲爱的弗兰克已经不在了
Sweetheart, Frank's not here.
都给我滚出我弟的房子
Get out of my brother's house!
杰克森
Jackson.
哈利
Harry.
Harry!
找到合脚的那双了吗?
Did you find the right size?
你好
Hello.
是宝宝吗?
Is it a baby?
-是宝宝 -是男孩吗?
- A baby. - A boy?
我不知道 也许吧
I don't know. I think, maybe.
是男孩
It is.
哦
Oh?
别让他一个人哭着
Don't leave him to cry.
我不会
I won't.
你知道吗 他来的时候会先像只猫
You know, when he comes, he's a cat.
又像熊 又像宝宝
He's a bear and a baby.
他也是你 是你们所有人
And he's you, he's all of you.
他会很有趣的
He's gonna be so funny.
嗨 找到想要的东西了吗?
Hi. Find everything you're looking for?
你是说人生吗?
In life?
车要加油吗?
Any gas for your car?
-不用 -行
- No. - Alrighty.
我超爱这玩意 不管里面加了什么 简直像魔法
I love this stuff. Whatever they put in that powder, it's like magic.
你要再拿一袋的话 两袋一起六美元
It's two for six dollars if you want another.
不用了
I'm good.
这一袋四美元 另一袋两美元
This one's four.And the other one is two.
我知道了 不用了 谢了
I get it.No, thanks.
是个男孩 对吧?
He's a boy, right?
他好可爱 嗨 小帅哥
He's so cute. Hi there, handsome.
嗨 小甜心
Hi there, sweetie-pie.
-他有名字吗?-没有
- Does he have a name? - No.
我们决定先不给他起名
We decided not to name him.
哦
Oh.
宝贝你几个月了?等等 让我猜猜
How old are you, sweetie? Wait. Let me guess.
我特别擅长这个 大概六个月?
I'm really good at this. About six months?
你为什么要一直说话?
Why are you talking?
你说话之前有想过自己要说什么 或者为什么要开口吗?
Do you ever think about what you'll say or why you're speaking?
还是一张嘴就叭叭说个不停?
Or do you just open your mouth and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah?
再过差不多三十秒我就走了 我们没必要聊天
In about 30 seconds, I'll be gone. We don't need to speak.
好
Okay.
每当你靠近一点 我就再多露一点真心
...every time you move I let a little more show
你可以好好利用我 所以别拒绝我 米基
There's something you can use So don't say no, Mickey
来吧 给我你能给的一切
So, come on and give it to me Anyway you can
不管你怎么玩 我都照单全收
Anyway you wanna do it I'll take it like a man
但求你 宝贝 别把我一个人晾在这潮湿里 米基
But please, baby, please Don't leave me in the damp, Mickey
噢 米基 真可惜你还是不懂
Oh, Mickey, what a pity You don't understand
你牵着我手时也抓住了我的心
You take me by the heart When you take me by the hand
噢 米基 你这么迷人 难道你就不明白吗?
Oh, Mickey, you're so pretty Can't you understand?
就是你这样的家伙 米基
It's guys like you, Mickey
噢 你对我做的一切 米基米基
Oh, what you do, Mickey, do, Mickey
别伤我的心 米基
Don't break my heart, Mickey
噢 米基 你太迷人 迷得我魂不守舍
Oh, Mickey, you're so fine You're so fine you blow my mind
嘿 米基 嘿 米基
Hey, Mickey! Hey, Mickey!
噢 米基 你太迷人 迷得我神魂颠倒
Oh, Mickey, you're so fine You're so fine you blow my mind
嘿 米基 嘿 米基
Hey, Mickey! Hey, Mickey!
你以为自己全都对 可我觉得你全都错
You think you've got the right But I think you've got it wrong
真可惜 你还是不懂
...what a pity, you don't understand
你抓住了我的心…
You take me by the heart and you-
好吧
Alrighty.
好吧 好吧 好吧
Alrighty. Alrighty. Alrighty.
-嗨 -嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
宝贝 你怎么起来了?
What you doing up, little bug?
我无聊
I was bored.
你无聊就把宝宝也弄醒了?
You got bored, so you kept the baby up?
我给你准备了点东西
I got somethin' for you.
你搞什么啊 杰克森?
What the fuck, Jackson?
你弄了条狗回来?
You got a dog?
弄了条狗
Got a dog.
你看看
Look at him.
我们需要的是猫啊
We need a cat.
好好好好
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
好狗 乖狗狗
Good dog. Good baby.
你是个乖狗狗 对 你最乖
You're a good baby. Yes, you are.
嘿
Hey.
过来
Come here.
快来
Come on.
就我一个被落下
Everyone but me!
嘿
Hey.
想看魔术吗?
Wanna see some magic?
想不想看魔术?
Wanna see a magic trick?
搅一搅 你来搅一搅
Stir it up. You stir it up.
第二步
Second.
魔法来了
Magic.
准备好了吗? 我们要发动 好
Ready? We're ready to steer. Okay.
准备好开车了吗?
Ready to drive?
开去月亮那边
To the moon.
然后向左拐去纽约
And a left to New York.
那是什么?
What is that?
你感觉到没?
Do you feel that?
你现在人在哪?
Where are you now?
在南帕外面84号公路边上一家汉堡店
In a burger place outside of Nampa. 84.
在吃东西?
You're eating?
嗯
Mm-hmm.
吃汉堡?
A burger?
对
Yep.
-好吃不?-嗯还行
- Is it good? - Yeah, it's alright.
那你还干了什么?
Well, what else have you been doing?
工作啊
Workin'.
嗯
Uh-huh.
还有呢?
What else?
都还好吗?
Is everything alright?
我在问你这一天过得怎样 就聊聊天
I'm asking you about your day. This is a conversation.
你最近都在干嘛?
What have you been up to?
没干嘛
Nothin'.
你有在写东西吗?
Have you been writing?
我快到了再打给你 好吗?
I'll call you when I get closer, okay?
那你回来到还想吃点什么吗?
Well, are you gonna wanna eat?
想啊 我回来咱们一起吃晚饭
Yeah, we can have dinner when I get back.
不过可能会有点晚
It's gonna be kind of late, though.
你这边还要点别的吗?
Anything else for you?
晚饭你想吃点什么?
What sounds good for supper?
孩子怎么样?
How's the boy?
他在睡觉
He's sleeping.
嘿 亲爱的 这是账单
Hey, darlin'. Here's the check.
好 回头再聊谢谢你 宝贝
Alright, talk later. Thank you, baby.
好再见
Okay.Bye.
潘姆
Pam?
我靠
Fuck!
靠 哦 真是要命
Fuck! Oh, goddammit.
潘姆 你搞什么鬼?
Pam, what the hell?
你悄悄溜进来的啊
You snuck in.
我没溜
I didn't sneak.
我把宝宝也带来了
I brought the baby.
-你把宝宝带来了 - 他睡着呢
- You brought the baby. - He's asleep.
- 那挺好 - 嗯
- That's nice. - Yeah.
只要你别把我脑袋打开花
As long as you don't blow my brains out.
那玩意里上子弹了吗 潘姆?
That thing loaded, Pam?
当然 那是哈利的枪
Oh, yeah. It's Harry's.
他以前睡觉时都把它放在身边
He used to sleep with it next to him.
那样他才觉得踏实
Made him feel safe.
我现在不知道该怎么处理这些东西
I don't know what to do with it now.
我根本不知道这些东西该怎么弄
I don't know what to do with any of it.
我从来不打理头发
I never do my hair.
挺好看的
It's pretty.
哈利喜欢我散着
Harry likes it loose.
是吗?
Yeah?
你最近睡眠好吗?
Are you sleeping at all?
嗯…
Um...
你知道的
You know.
杰克森说你最近老是梦游
Jackson says you've been sleepwalking.
哦对是啊
Oh, yeah. That.
你会走多远?
You get far?
我在卡尔弗路上醒过来 嗓子都喊哑了
Woke up on Culver Road screaming my head off.
以前从没这样过
Never done anything like that before.
从那之后 什么都不像真的了
Nothing seems real since...
自他死了以后
since he died.
我脑子好像…
My brain just seems...
碎成了一块块
chopped up.
嗯
Yeah.
我是你奶奶 对 我是
I'm your grandma. Yeah, I am.
你们俩肯接手这房子真是太好了
It's so wonderful the two of you have taken on the house.
嗯
Mm-hmm.
哦 弗兰克他…
Oh, he was...
小时候可开心了
such a happy little guy, Frank.
他是开枪自杀的?
He shot himself?
-弗兰克叔叔?- 对
- Uncle Frank? - Yes.
然后是你发现他的?
And you found him?
是我
I did.
-那一定很可怕 -是我找到他的很可怕
- That must have been awful. - Yes, I did. It was.
确实很可怕
It was.
打在头上?
In the head?
打头上?
不是
No.
-我记不… - 那到底是哪呢?
- I can't... - Well, where, then?
心脏?胸口?
The heart? Chest?
不是
No.
-腿 脚 背?-都不是
- Legs, feet, back? - No.
-胳膊还是肚子?-不 都不是
- Arms? Stomach? - No, no.
鸡鸡?
Dick?
-格蕾丝 -屁股?
-Grace. - Ass?
天啊 他故意朝自己屁股开枪?
Oh, my God. He shot himself in his own ass intentionally?
你知道吗 他长得真像你
You know, he looks just like you.
-弗兰克叔叔?-不是
- Uncle Frank? - No.
是宝宝啊 你这傻丫头
The baby, you goose.
你觉得像?
You think?
嗯
Yeah
格蕾丝 你知道 刚当妈头一年谁都会有点不正常
Grace, you know, everybody goes a little loopy the first year.
-是吗?-是啊
-Yeah? - Yeah.
你跟哈利认识一辈子了
You and Harry have known each other your whole lives.
你当然也会有点不正常
Of course you're gonna go a bit loopy.
不不不 我是说你
No, no. I mean you.
生完孩子之后
After a baby.
我妈当年就疯了 珍也崩溃过
My mother went nuts. Jen lost it.
我有阵子也找不到自己 但你会…你会…
I didn't feel myself for a while. But you'll... you'll...
你会回来的
You'll come back.
你知道…
You know...
- 要是你过得很难… - 我挺好的
- if you're having a hard time... - I feel fine.
我们很快再来
We'll come again soon.
谢谢你泡的茶
Thanks for the tea.
是谁在推你?
Who's pushing you?
是幽灵吗?
Is that a ghost?
红色和黄色
Red and yellow
粉色和绿色
And pink and green
紫色 橙色和蓝色
Purple and orange and blue
我能唱出一道彩虹来
I can sing a rainbow
唱一首彩虹之歌
Sing a rainbow
也唱一首彩虹之歌
Sing a rainbow too
用你的眼睛去听
Listen with your eyes
把你看见的全都唱出来
And sing everything you see
你他妈想干嘛?
What the fuck do you want?
给你嘴唇划开
Cut your lip.
划开
Cut it.
你就扔这儿不管了?
Just gonna leave it?
-它可是你小情人你收拾 -真有你的
- He's your girlfriend. You clean it up. - Nice.
它还往地上撒了泡尿
He pissed on the floor too.
你该擦亮眼睛看看自己往家里带了什么
You should make better choices in who you bring home.
-拜托格蕾丝 -你冲我发火?
Fuck's sake, Grace. You're mad at me?
你怎么不放它出去 你这疯女人
Why didn't you let him out, you whack job?
不关我的事
He's not my problem.
你就给它拴上绳子 牵到后面去
Just put him on his leash, take him out the back
等它习惯这地方
until he gets used to where he is.
我才不要给你那条破狗当训犬师
Yeah, I'm not gonna train your fucking dog.
我们有个宝宝
We have a baby.
废话
No shit.
我受不了这样…这地方简直是个破坑
I can't have this... This place is a fucking hole.
-是你把我们弄进来的 -我在挣钱
- And you moved us into it. - I am working.
然后我回到家还得收拾所有烂摊子
And when I come home, I'm the one cleaning everything up.
是啊 一周就三天 要不要给你颁个奖章?
Yeah, three days a week. Let me shower you in medals.
-闭嘴 -你居然把烟灰缸放在地毯上
- Shut up. - You have an ashtray on the carpet.
你就不怕宝宝吃进去吗?
You don't think the baby's eating that shit?
闭嘴
Shut up.
你让我们搬进你叔叔自杀的房子
Move us into the house where your uncle shot himself
还是他妈朝自己屁股开的枪
up the fucking ass.
-我的天-打的屁股 他妈的打的屁股
- Oh, my God. - Up the ass. Up the fucking ass.
-住手 -我知道 我知道
- Stop. - I knew it. I knew it.
你裤头怎么开着?你干嘛不穿裤头?
Why are your shorts undone? Why do you not have your shorts on?
- 闭嘴 - 天啊…
- Shut up. - Jesus Chr-
一副他妈道貌岸然的德行
Fucking sanctimonious dick.
说不定是你自己尿在地上 然后怪到狗头上
You probably pissed on the floor yourself. Blamed it on the dog.
明明是你那条脏狗干的 还有“道貌岸然”的意思是
It was your mangy dog. And "sanctimonious" means
你自以为比别人高尚 懂吗 蠢人?
you think you're morally superior to other people, dummy.
-顺便问一句你那本书写得怎样了?-好极了 多谢关心
-- How's the book going, by the way? - Fantastic, thank you!
你那本伟大的美国小说
Your Great American Novel.
女主正准备拿锤子把她老公活活砸死
The main character's about to batter her husband to death with a hammer.
-听着就一塌糊涂 -反正你也不识字
- Sounds like shit. - Well, you can't read, so...
要是我少花点时间把手伸进裤裆里
Maybe if I spend a little less time with my hands down my pants
多花点时间写作
and a little more time writing,
说不定我真能写出点东西来
maybe I'd write something, maybe.
我手伸在裤裆里
My hands are down my pants
是因为你那玩意哪里都插 就是不插我这儿来 混蛋
'cause you put your dick everywhere except there, asshole!
你要把孩子吵醒了
You're gonna wake up the baby.
现在你倒开始担心孩子了
Now you're worried about the baby.
我一直都在担心这孩子
I'm always worried about the fucking baby.
-我们出去兜兜风 -不去
- We're going for a drive. - No.
-去非去不可 -我不去
- Yes! We are. - No!
-上车格蕾丝 -滚远点
- Get in, Grace. - Fuck off.
-我们得谈谈 - 就在这谈
- We need to talk. - We can talk here.
-给我上车 -老娘说不
- Get in the fucking car! - Fucking no!
杰克森 我不会把孩子丢在家里
Jackson, I'm not leaving the baby.
住手 住手 住手
Stop, stop, stop.
我不能丢下孩子 杰克森
I'm not leaving the baby. Jackson!
-孩子没事 -停 停
- The baby's fine. - Stop! Stop!
你真是个他妈的混蛋
You're a fucking... fucking asshole!
你到底在干嘛啊?
What is wrong with you?
-认真的? -把安全带给我扣上
- Seriously? - Give me the belt.
哦 天啊
Oh, my God.
你敢开门试试
Don't you dare open the door.
格蕾丝
Gracie.
嘿 伙计 别…
Hey, bud, don't...
停 停
Stop.Stop!
听着 好吗 我.…只是觉得
Look, okay, I... I just think
我们得有个作息表什么的 或者说…
we need to have a schedule or somethin', or just...
我就是想先定个计划 因为我…
I just wanna make a plan 'cause I...
格蕾丝 我不想让你觉得我不懂感激
Grace, I don't want you to think that I don't appreciate
你做的这一切 我只是…
everything that you do, I just...
你是家里的顶梁柱 你是主心骨 你是当家的 但是
Like, you're the glue, you're the one, you're the OG, but...
要是你自己感觉不好 那么…
If you're not feeling good, then...
我想也许我们得好好谈谈
then, I don't know, maybe we should, like, talk about it.
我只是想让你知道我一直都在
I just want you to know that I'm here.
要孩子真的是这辈子最…
Having a baby is like the most...
天翻地覆的大事…
monumental fucking thing and...
我懂 我想让你知道我有多明白
I get that, I want you to know how much I get that,
如果你想聊聊 那…
and if you wanna talk about it, then...
能把这东西关掉吗
Can we turn this off?
什么?
What?
音乐啊 能不能关掉?
The music. Can we turn it off?
-这可是经典歌曲 -好
- It's a classic. - Okay.
我不管我就是讨厌这歌我讨厌吉他
I don't care. I hate it. I hate guitars.
-什么时候开始的?-一直都讨厌
- Since when? - Since forever.
什么?你疯了吧 谁会讨厌吉他啊?
What? That's insane. Who hates guitars?
你才不讨厌吉他
You don't hate guitars.
格蕾丝 我知道你在想什么 那不过是一盒旧的
Grace. I know what you're thinking, but that's just an old pack.
它在那放了很久 你以前就见过
It's been in there forever. You've seen them before.
- 我以前见过?- 见过
- I've seen these before? - Yes.
你看 那些只是… 是格雷格的东西
Look, they're just... they're Greg's.
哇 你和格雷格感情可真好
Wow, you and Greg are very, very close.
够了 够了 够了
Stop it. Stop it. Stop it.
够了 格蕾丝 别他妈烦人了
Stop it. Grace, stop being fucking annoying.
你快跑 你快跑
You can run, you can run
去告诉我那朋友威利·布朗
Tell my friend boy Willie Brown
你快跑 你快跑
You can run, you can run
我站在十字路口 相信自己要往下沉
And I'm standing at the crossroads Believe I'm sinking down
我来了
I'm coming!
宝贝 妈妈在这呢
I'm here, baby.
他不喘气了
He's not breathing.
很好笑
Funny.
去他妈的
Fuck it.
哈利?
Harry?
起来
Up.
格蕾丝?
Grace?
你得把那条狗打死
You have to shoot the dog.
什么
What?
你得把那条狗一枪打死
You have to shoot the fucking dog.
它在哭叫
He's crying.
你他妈从哪儿找出来的?
Where the fuck you found that?
你心爱的狗狗正在受罪
That thing you love is suffering.
-你疯了吗?- 你可以的
- Have you lost your mind? - You can fix it.
-你疯了吗?-它很疼
- Are you insane? - He's in pain.
-明天我带它去看兽医 -他们会给它安乐死的
- I'll take it to the vet tomorrow. - And they'll put it down.
格蕾丝 求你了 我不会亲手杀掉我的狗好吗?
Grace, please! I'm not gonna kill my dog. Okay?
你嘴唇怎么样了?
How's your lip?
对不起
I'm sorry.
你每天早上都是怎么过的 格蕾丝?
How do you start your days, Grace?
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
就是…
Well...
做瑜伽?
Yoga?
跑步 还是喝点柠檬热水?
Running? Hot water and lemon?
写作?
Writing?
你写作这块怎么样了?
What's happened with your writing?
我文思枯竭了
I can't do it any more.
为什么?
Why not?
你知道现在谁在教瑜伽吗?
You know who's teaching yoga?
-谁啊?-你那邻居 是叫梅丽莎?
- Who? - That neighbour of yours, Melissa?
她在网上直播教学 她…
She does it over the internet. She...
也许你可以跟她学学?
Maybe you could take a class with her?
潘姆 我觉得那可不叫瑜伽
I don't think that's yoga, Pam.
哦 我…
Oh, I'm...
我还挺确定那就是
I'm pretty sure it is.
嗯…
Well..
对年轻女人来说 可能挺放松的
it might be a relaxing thing for a young woman to do.
你还是这么漂亮 格蕾丝
You're still so pretty, Grace.
让我帮你吧 亲爱的
Let me help you, sweetie.
不管是带孩子 还是收拾房子 什么都行
Just with the baby, with... with the house, whatever you need.
只是…
Just...
想多给你点时间做别的事
give you more time to do other things.
找到了
Alright.
你找到点货啊
You found some..
这是好东西 妈
It's the good stuff, Mom.
这牌子我认识
I know this brand.
这款现在最火
This is the hot one.
我要出去走走
I'm going for a walk.
-我一会儿就回来 -格蕾丝?
- I won't be long. - Grace?
你落在四周 像敲打出一段旋律
...beating a tune as you fall all around
滴滴答答 小小四月阵雨
Drip, drip, drop Little April shower
有什么能比得上你动听的声音?
What can compare With your beautiful sound?
多动听的声音 多动听的声音
Beautiful sound, beautiful sound
滴滴答答 小小四月阵雨
Drip, drip, drop Little April shower
你落在四周 敲打出一段旋律
Beating a tune as you fall all around
滴滴答答 小小四月阵雨
Drip, drip, drop Little April shower
有什么能比得上你动听的声音?
What can compare With your beautiful sound?
天空阴沉时 滴滴答答
Drip, drip, drop When the sky is cloudy
你就来了 带着那可爱的歌声一起来
You come along Come along with your pretty little song
天空阴沉时 滴滴答答
Drip, drip, drop When the sky is cloudy
你就来了 带着那可爱的歌声一起来
You come along Come along with your pretty little song
轻快的小回旋曲 轻快的小回旋曲
Gay little roundelay Gay little roundelay
雨天的歌 雨天的歌
Song of the rainy day Song of the rainy day
我多爱听你那细碎的拍打声
How I love to hear your patter Pretty little pitter-patter
当你倾盆而下时一片忙乱
Helter-skelter when you pelter
烦心事似乎都跟着消散
Troubles always seem to scatter
滴滴答答 小小四月阵雨
Drip, drip drop Little April shower
格蕾丝?
Grace?
格蕾丝 你听得到我们吗?
Grace! Can you hear us?
格蕾丝
Grace!
-格蕾丝 -格蕾丝
- Grace! - Grace.
格蕾丝
Grace!
她抱着你家孩子消失好几个小时
She took your baby and disappeared for hours.
把你急疯了
Had you frantic.
现在她还不跟你说话吗?
And now she's not talking to you?
她只是想自己一个人静一静 我能理解
She just needs some time to herself. You know, I get that.
不 杰克森
No, Jackson.
她现在状态不对
She is not well.
妈 有时候人状态确实会不太好
Well, sometimes people aren't well, Mom.
事情变了 人是需要点时间适应的
Sometimes people need some time to adjust when things change.
有时候大家都得拿出点耐心
Sometimes everybody just needs to have some fucking patience
相信状况会慢慢好起来的
and trust that things will get better.
你现在还会梦游吗?
Are you still sleepwalking?
我只是想帮忙
I'm just trying to help.
你确实是在帮忙啊 妈
Well, you are helping, Mom.
她只是需要一点空间 去…去写东西
She just needs some space to... to write.
她说自己写不出来
She says she can't.
这就好比 你知道…
It's just like, you know...
大概就是写作瓶颈之类的吧
It's just writer's block or whatever, I guess.
不要 我不想进去
No. I don't wanna get in.
好了 真棒
Okay, there we are. Good job.
-嗨 -好啦你真是个勇敢的大姑娘
- Hi. - Alright, that's a big girl.
真是个大姑娘
That's a big girl.
-我不想去 -没事的
- I don't wanna go. - It's okay.
-打扰一下 -嗯?
- Sorry to bother you. - Huh?
我车轮好像瘪了
I think my car might have a flat tyre.
能帮我看一眼吗?
Would you mind just taking a look at it?
-深呼吸 -不要
- Breathe. - No!
看妈妈 嘿 看看妈妈这边
Look at Mommy. Hey, look at Mommy.
宝贝 我们没时间折腾这些 不行
Babe, we don't have any time for this. No.
所以…
So...
你能不能…
could you...
好 行 抱歉
Okay.Yeah, sorry.
把腿收回车里
Put your leg in the car.
还好吗?
Alright?
我们上次做是什么时候?
When was the last time we had sex?
随便猜猜看
Rough guess.
我真说不上来 格蕾丝
I really couldn't say, Gracie.
来 随便蒙一个
Go on, take a stab.
不知道 一个月前?
I don't know. Like a month?
再猜 两个半月
Try two and a half.
这阵子情况嘛 你也知道
Well, things have been, you know.
而且那次是凌晨四点 你基本上都睡着了
And it was four in the morning and you were essentially asleep.
格蕾丝
Grace.
再往前一次
And the time before that,
我们在看那个荒岛纪录片
we were watching TV about that thing on the island,
我求你半天 然后你铺了条毛巾
and I was begging you, and you put a towel down.
好了好了好了
Alright, alright, alright.
以前明明挺好的 对吧?
It used to be good, right?
现在也还是很好 格蕾丝
It's still good, Grace.
根本已经不存在了 杰克森 没这回事了
It doesn't exist, Jackson. It's not a thing.
好吧 我会多用点心
Alright, I'm gonna put more effort in.
今晚吗?
Tonight?
-好 -你还想要我吗?
- Okay. - You want me?
想啊 我想
Yeah, I want you.
再说一遍
Say it again.
我…我想要你 对
I... I want you, yeah.
-晚饭前还是晚饭后?-格蕾丝 你真是的
- Before or after dinner? - Grace, man.
-能不能有点他妈的主见 -天啊 真是受够了
- Just have a fucking opinion. - Jesus fucking Christ!
等我们回家以后?
When we get home?
行
Yeah.
我们一回家就做?
You'll fuck me when we get home?
行
Yeah.
在车里?
In the car?
如果你想的话
If you like.
我们以前总在车里做 记得吗?
We used to fuck in the car all the time, remember?
嗯
Uh-huh.
我解开安全带 爬到你这边 然后你就上我?
I'll unbuckle, come over to your seat and you'll fuck me?
对
Yes.
别闹了 我妈就在那里呢
Come on. My mom's right there.
那你就快点上我
Fuck me quickly, then.
别…
I don't...
格蕾丝 别这样 我只是有点…
Grace, come on. I'm just kinda...
你这没用的阳痿废物
You impotent piece of shit.
一无是处的死基佬
You useless fucking faggot!
你他妈疯了
You're fucking insane.
疯得一塌糊涂
Fucking insane.
都还好吧?
Everything okay?
-开门 我要上厕所 -去外面尿去
- Open the door. I need to use it. - Piss outside.
我又不是要尿尿
I don't need to piss.
那就拉到草丛里去 关我屁事
Shit in a bush. I don't care.
天啊 格蕾丝
Oh, God, Grace!
格蕾丝
Grace!
我不想拉草丛里 我想在马桶上拉
I don't wanna shit in a bush. I wanna shit in the toilet.
快点 我要憋不住了
Come on, it's coming out.
快点啊
Come on.
一会儿就要拉得满地都是了
It's gonna be all over the floor.
我已经闻到味儿了
I'm starting to smell it.
快点
Quick.
谢谢
Thank you.
我的天
Jesus Christ.
拜托别跑
No running, please.
-嗨 进来吧 -嘿
- Hi. Hey! Come on in. - Hey.
格雷格
Greg!
是啊 格雷格说咱这点吃的够全村人吃了
Yeah. Greg said we have enough food to feed a village.
反正我们就准备了这么多 是吧?
Well, that's what we've got, right?
那你们就再把这些算上吧
Well, you can add these, I guess.
在车上给颠翻了 之前好看多了
They fell over in the car. They looked better before.
你手指怎么了?
What happened to your fingers?
想给你烤个蛋糕 把手给烫了
I burnt them trying to bake you a cake.
-嘿 兄弟 -你来了 兄弟 欢迎啊
- Hey, man. - There you are. Welcome, buddy.
-见到你真高兴 -我也是 老兄
- Good to see you. - You too, man.
-嗨 -这地方布置得真不错
- Hi. - The place looks great.
你家宝宝真漂亮
He's such a beautiful baby.
-杰克 来 我给你倒杯喝的 -他要不要吃点小零食?
- Jack, let's get you a drink. - Does he want a snack?
-好啊 跟其他小孩吃一样就行 -行他不过敏吧?
-- Sure. Whatever the kids are having. - Okay. No allergies?
不过敏 应该没有
No. I don't think so.
谁是小甜心呀?
Who's a sweetie-pie?
这是杰克的宝贝儿子
Here's Jack's boy.
你们看见这个了吗
Did you guys see this?
那你们还会再要一个吗?
So, you think you'll have another one?
会啊 现在已经怀上了 一次来俩
Yeah. Pregnant now. Cookin' up twins.
你手怎么了?
What happened to your hands?
哦
Oh.
你该看看那面墙
You should see the wall.
是啊 我…
Yeah, I...
我现在有两个孩子 然后…
I have two kids, and...
说实话 两个已经够多了
and two is a lot, if I'm being honest.
看得出来
Seems like it.
不过 宝宝是真的很难带
Babies, though, babies are hard.
我觉得没人把这件事讲够
I don't think anybody talks about that enough.
所有人都在说这个
It's all anyone talks about.
整个人都会变掉的
It changes you.
头六个月我差点疯了
I think I nearly lost my mind for the first six months.
那你觉得什么时候能好?
When do you think you'll be getting it back?
你知道吗 产后抑郁比大家以为的
You know, postnatal depression is so much more common
常见多了
than people think.
-格蕾丝你平时做什么工作?- 我不工作
- What do you do for work, Grace? - I don't.
我现在就卡在既想做点什么 又完全不想…
I'm stuck between wanting to do something and not wanting to d...
做之间
anything at all.
等等 雪莉说过你是个作家
Hang on. Cheryl mentioned that you're a writer.
真不错 那一定挺好的
That's cute. That must be nice.
能围着孩子穿插着做点事
Having something you can squeeze around a baby.
不 我现在已经不写了
Yeah, I don't do that anymore.
怎么不写了?没灵感了?
Why not? Stuck for inspiration?
我相信会回来的
I'm sure it'll come back.
格蕾丝?
Grace?
格蕾丝
Grace!
杰克森?杰克森?看着我 好吗 嘿
Jackson? Jackson? Look at me, okay? Hey.
-还能呼吸吗?-谁去倒点水来
- Can you breathe? - Somebody get some water.
-杰克森 -我打电话叫人
- Jackson? - Let me call someone.
-怎么了 胸口疼?-嗯
- What, your chest hurts? -- Yeah.
你还能呼吸 跟着我一起呼吸
You can breathe. Breathe with me.
对吧 你看?
Yeah. See?
好 你没事 你没事的
Yeah, you're okay. You're okay.
他没事了
He's okay.
这算是个提醒 你懂吧?
It's just kind of a wake-up call, you know.
格蕾丝 我们得互相照顾
We need to look out for each other, Grace.
我现在压力真的很大
I am getting really stressed.
什么压力?
About what?
没人动我们的点心 你看到了吗?
No one took our pastries. You see that?
有一大堆别的吃的呢
Well, there was a ton of food.
很没礼貌
It's rude.
人家不是没礼貌 别这样
They weren't being rude. Come on.
你知道什么才叫没礼貌吗 格蕾丝?
You know what's rude, Grace?
穿着他妈的内衣跳进一池子小孩中间游泳
Getting into a pool full of kids in your fucking underwear.
那才叫没礼貌
That's what's rude.
你让我很丢脸
You embarrassed me.
你让我们俩都丢脸了
You embarrassed us.
格蕾丝 格蕾丝
Grace.Grace!
我靠
Goddammit!
我靠 真他妈的
Fuck me. Jesus fucking Christ.
以后别再这样了
Don't ever do that again.
听见没?
Alright?
艾米莉娅还是个小女孩的时候
When Amelia was a little girl,
她喜欢幻想自己能展开翅膀
she liked to imagine she could stretch her wings
像鸟儿一样飞起来
and fly like a bird.
有一天她坐上了飞机
One day she got to ride on an airplane
喜欢得再也不愿落地
and liked it so much she didn't wanna ever come down.
世界看起来那么小
The world looked so small,
房子和车子都像玩具一样
the houses and cars were like toys.
她们飞了成千上万里路
They flew for thousands of miles.
越过海洋和丛林
Over oceans and jungles.
有人说她们疯了
Some people thought they were crazy.
可艾米莉娅一点也不怕经历千百次冒险
But Amelia wasn't afraid of having a thousand adventures.
于是她继续像鸟一样 飞得比所有人都要远
So she flew on like a bird, further than anyone had gone before,
再也没有回来
never to return.
什么鬼?
What the fuck?
你想结婚吗?
You wanna get married?
想
Yeah.
想 他妈的当然想了
Yeah, fuck yeah.
她不爱吃溏心蛋
She don't like Her eggs all runny
她觉得翘二郎腿很好玩
She thinks crossin' her legs is funny
她对金钱不屑一顾
She looks down her nose at money
她疯起来像复活节的兔子
She gets it on like the Easter Bunny
她是我的宝贝 我是她的甜心
She's my baby, I'm her honey
我永远不会放她走
Never gonna let her go
他有很久没碰过女人
He ain't got laid In a month of Sundays
有回我撞见他在闻我的内裤
I caught him once And he was sniffin' my undies
他脑子不太灵光但却能成事
He ain't too sharp But he gets things done
喝起啤酒来像在呼吸空气
Drinks his beer like it's oxygen
他是我的宝贝 我是他的甜心
He's my baby and I'm his honey
我这辈子都不会放他走
I'm never gonna let him go
就算再怎么不成体统
In spite of ourselves
最后也会一起坐在彩虹上
We'll end up a-sittin' on a rainbow
哪怕所有人都不看好
Against all odds
亲爱的咱俩就是那头奖大奖
Honey, we're the big door prize
宁可割掉鼻子也要跟自己较劲到底
We're gonna spite Our noses right off of our faces
到头来眼里只剩两颗心在欢跳
There won't be nothing' But big old hearts dancin' in our eyes
天啊 真的假的?
Oh, my God. Really?
吻我
Kiss me.
-吻我 -格蕾丝
- Kiss me. - Grace.
我不知道杰克森在哪
I don't know where Jackson is.
我们去找找你那没用的老公吧
Let's go find that no-count husband of yours.
哇
Wow.
你好 我是新娘 在新娘套房
Hello. This is the bride in the bridal suite.
想问能不能给我房间送一桶冰上来
I was wondering if I could get a bucket of ice sent up to my room.
本楼层有制冰机
We've got an ice machine on your floor
就在走廊尽头
at the end of the corridor there.
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
查理
Charlie.
查理 能麻烦你帮我弄一桶上来吗?
Charlie, would you mind getting it for me, please?
我现在不太方便下楼
I'm a little indisposed.
我们不提供送冰服务 女士
We don't bring up ice, ma'am.
好吧
Okay.
你还在听吗?
Are you still there?
在的 女士 还有什么能帮您的?
Yes, ma'am. Is there anything else I can help you with?
嗯…我老公现在在楼下的宴会上
Well, my husband is at the party downstairs.
我们婚礼的宴会
Our wedding.
我在想 要是我们回房时香槟已经冰好了
Um... and I think it would be really nice
他一定会很高兴
if the champagne was cold for him when we came up.
我明白
I understand.
我只是想做个好太太
I'm just trying to be a good wife.
是 不好意思 这个我帮不了
Yes. Sorry, but I can't help with that.
查理 你的声音真好听
You have a really beautiful voice, Charlie.
谢谢 女士
Thank you, ma'am.
我心中的野兽
The beast in me
已学会与痛苦共存
Has had to learn to live with pain
学会躲避风雨
And how to shelter from the rain
转眼之间
And in the twinkling of an eye
就得被人牢牢拴住
Might have to be restrained
上帝保佑
God help
我心中的野兽
The beast in me
那时候我大概…三岁吧?
I must have been about... three?
我跟爸妈一起去了海边
My parents and I went down to the beach.
他们大概在看书 也可能睡着了
They must have been reading, or maybe they fell asleep.
我把脚伸进水里
And I had my feet in the water,
然后有个女孩走过来
and then this girl came up to me.
她大概十岁左右
She must have been about ten,
可在我眼里 她就是那种…大人模样
but to me she seemed, you know, like a... like a grown-up.
她牵着我的手 我们一起走了一段路
And she took my hand and we walked for a while.
她给我买了根冰棍
She bought me an ice pop.
路人…
People would...
说我们俩好可爱
say how cute we were.
那感觉真的很好
It was really nice.
后来我爸妈发现我不见了 然后…
And then as my parents realised I was missing and...
我妈哭了
my mom was crying and...
我爸气疯了
my dad was really angry,
我记得当时我脑子里冒出一个念头
and I remember just thinking
“要是你们不是我爸妈就好了
"I wish you weren't mine.
我多希望…
"I wish...
我不是你们亲生的”
I didn't belong to you."
格蕾丝 你父母现在在哪儿?
Where are your parents now, Grace?
飞机失事去世了
They died in a plane crash.
那时你多大?
How old were you?
十岁
Ten.
那日子一定很不好过吧
It must have been terribly difficult.
所以 你可能会有点被抛弃的创伤感
Like, perhaps you have some abandonment issues.
让你很难安全地与人建立依存关系
Which makes it hard for you to safely attach to people.
比如对你丈夫 对你儿子
Your husband. To your son.
我跟我儿子没问题
I don't have a problem attaching to my son.
他很完美
He's perfect.
糟糕的是其他所有的一切
It's everything else that's fucked.
嗨
Hi!
嗨 宝贝
Hi, baby.
哦 妈妈想死你了
Oh, I missed you.
怎么了?
What?
你租的车?
You got a rental?
不啊 是我们的 从格雷格那里弄的
No, it's ours. I got it off Greg.
你哪来的钱?
With what money?
别操心 他能搞定
Don't worry about it. He's taking care of us.
你喜欢吗?
You like it?
嗯 挺酷的 够大
Yeah, it's cool. Big.
开大点声 我喜欢这歌
Turn this up. I love this song.
记得你说过不喜欢吉他的
Thought you didn't like guitars.
我什么时候说过?我可爱死吉他了
When did I ever say that? I love guitars.
你愿留在我们的爱情故事里吗?
Will you stay In our lovers' story?
若你留下 绝不会后悔
If you stay, you won't be sorry
因为我们相信你
'Cause we believe in you
你很快就会长大 何不试一试
Soon you'll grow, so take a chance
跟这对爱做梦的怪人一起谈情说爱
With a couple of kooks Hung up on romancing
你愿留在我们的爱情故事里吗?
Will you stay in our lovers' story?
若你留下 绝不会后悔
If you stay, you won't be sorry
还好吧 小子 来
Doing alright there, bud? Come on, now.
他好可爱
He's so cute.
我好喜欢他这顶小帽子
I love his little hat.
他其实不太爱戴 对吧 小家伙?
He's not really a fan. Are you, buddy?
我平常也给一个差不多大的宝宝当保姆 不过你家的更可爱
I babysit a kid just like him. Yours is cuter, though.
他下过水了吗?
Has he been in the water yet?
还没有
No, not yet.
我们可以带他到水边去
We could take him to the edge.
你觉得他会跟我们走吗?
Do you think he'll go with us?
会的 你很爱交际 对吧?
Yeah. You're very social, aren't you?
要是他想 我们还能帮他堆个城堡
We can make him a castle if he wants.
我们就走到那儿 你看得见的
If we go just there, we'll be in sight.
想跟她们一起去吗 小家伙?
Wanna go with 'em, buddy?
来跟我玩吗?
Play with me?
他叫什么?
What's his name?
哈利
Harry.
来吧哈利
Come on, Harry.
那是什么?
What is that?
是啊 他妈的当然是
Yeah, fuck yeah.
别这样了
Stop it!
你刚才睡着的时候一直在说对不起
You kept saying sorry when you were sleeping.
我进来的时候 你还在说
When I came in, you were saying it.
为什么道歉?
What are you sorry about?
我不记得了
I don't remember.
你觉得需要为任何事情道歉吗?
Do you think you need to apologise for anything?
没有
No.
我必须起来吗?
Do I have to get up?
不用 格蕾丝 你什么都不用做
No, Grace. You don't need to do anything.
我可以一直躺着?
I can just stay in bed?
如果你想的话
If that's what you want.
哦
Oh.
是你啊
It's you.
你好吗?
How are you?
大家都很想你
Everyone misses you.
宝贝 你要进来吗?
Coming in, babe?
嗯
Yeah.
我把这儿稍微收拾了一下
Fixed it up a little bit.
看起来不错
Looks nice.
嗯
Yeah.
温柔地爱我
Love me tender
甜蜜地爱我
Love me sweet
别让我…
Never let me...
你真漂亮 格蕾丝
You're so beautiful, Grace.
是你让我的人生如此完整
You have made my life complete
我也如此地爱你
And I love you so
温柔地爱我
Love me tender
真心地爱我
Love me true
让我的所有梦想都能实现
All my dreams fulfil
因为亲爱的 我爱你
For my darlin', I love you
我将永远爱你
And I always will
温柔地爱我
Love me tender
长久地爱我
Love me long
把我放进你心里
Take me to your heart
因为那里才是我的归宿
For it's there that I belong
我们将永不…
And we'll never...
哦 格蕾丝 你气色真好
Oh, Grace. You look so well.
-你能回家真是太好了 -你看上去好多了
- It's so great that you're home. - You look so healthy.
谢谢
Thanks.
有时候人就是需要离开一阵子 对吧?
Sometimes all we need is just a little break, right?
说真的 你和杰克森能拥有彼此挺幸运的
You know what? You and Jackson are really lucky to have each other.
嗯 是啊
Mm-hmm, yeah.
-格蕾丝 见到你真好 -我也是
- Grace, it is so good to see you. - You too.
-你看起来精神好多了 -谢谢
- You look so well. - Thank you.
我是说真的 你真的好多了
No, but really, you just look so much better.
你也是
You too.
你也好太多了
You look a lot better.
-这里都还好吧?-嗯 挺好的
- All good here? - Yeah, doing great.
我们都比以前好多了
We're both doing a lot better than we were.
-玩得开心吗?-开心极了
- You having a good time? - The best.
- 那就好 - 而且我真的特别感谢你
- That's good. - And I'm just so grateful to you.
把所有东西都顾得这么好
For taking care of everything.
还把房子刷了新漆…
And painting the house...
-还帮忙带孩子 -你真贴心
- Taking care of the baby. - That's sweet.
还把我送进那鬼地方 你真是太好了
Having me fucking committed. You're just the best.
-好了 格蕾丝 别闹了 -我说的是实话
- Okay, Grace, come on. - But I mean it.
-谢谢你啊 - 求你了 别这样
- Thank you. - Please. Don't do this.
别哪样?
Don't do what?
我开枪打死了一条狗 它当时很痛苦
I shot a dog! It was in pain.
我们来到这世上 为所欲为
We came to be and we ran amok!
愿我们长命百岁 然后断子绝孙
May we live long and die out.
没错
Yes.
愿我们长命百岁
May we live long
然后断子绝孙
and die out.
格蕾丝
Grace.
潘姆
Pam.
格蕾丝
Grace.
别管她 杰克森
Leave her be, Jackson.
格蕾丝
Grace!
格蕾丝你在哪?
Where are you, Grace?
我就在这儿
I'm right here.
只是你看不见我
You just can't see me.
我回不去了
I can't go back.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
约翰·普林这首歌 简直是开车神曲
Perfect driving tune right here from John Prine.
我可以再努力一点
I can try harder.
她不爱吃溏心蛋
She don't like Her eggs all runny
她觉得翘二郎腿很好玩
She thinks crossin' her legs is funny
她对金钱不屑一顾
She looks down her nose at money
她疯起来像复活节的兔子
She gets it on like the Easter Bunny
她是我的宝贝 我是她的甜心
She's my baby, I'm her honey
我永远不会放她走
I'm never gonna let her go
他有很久没碰过女人
He ain't got laid In a month of Sundays
有回我撞见他在闻我的内裤
Caught him once And he was sniffin' my undies
他脑子不太灵光 但却能成事
He ain't too sharp But he gets things done
喝起啤酒来像在呼吸空气
Drinks his beer like it's oxygen
他是我的宝贝 我是他的甜心
He's my baby, I'm his honey
我这辈子都不会放他走
Never gonna let him go
就算再怎么不成体统
In spite of ourselves
最后也会一起坐在彩虹上
We'll end up sittin' on a rainbow
哪怕所有人都不看好
Against all odds
亲爱的 咱俩就是那头奖大奖
Honey, we're the big door prize
宁可割掉鼻子也要跟自己较劲到底
We're gonna spite our noses Right off of our faces
到头来眼里只剩两颗心在欢跳
There won't be nothin' But big old hearts dancin' in our eyes
够了
Enough.
格蕾丝
Grace!
当乏味日常把人咬得生疼
When routine bites hard
当所有志气都已消磨殆尽
And ambitions are low
当怨恨逐渐高涨
And resentments ride high
情感却不再生长
But emotions won't grow
我们改变了方式
And we're changing our ways
走上不同的道路
Taking different roads
于是爱
Then love
爱会将我们撕裂
Love will tear us apart
一次又一次
Again
爱
Love
爱会将我们撕裂
Love will tear us apart
一次又一次
Again
为何卧室如此冰冷
- Why is the bedroom so cold?
你背过身去不再面对我
You've turned away on your side
是我的时机总不对吗?
Is my timing that flawed?
我们彼此的尊重都被磨得干枯
Our respect runs so dry
可心里仍有一种莫名的吸引
Yet there's still this appeal
一直陪着我们走到如今
That we've kept through our lives
但爱
But love
爱会将我们撕裂
Love will tear us apart
一次又一次
Again
爱
Love
爱会将我们撕裂
Love will tear us apart
一次又一次
Again
你在睡梦中呼喊
You cry out in your sleep
把我所有失败都照得通明
All my failings exposed
嘴里满是苦涩的味道
There's a taste in my mouth
当绝望渐渐将我吞噬
As desperation takes hold
原本如此美好的事物
Just that something so good
却再也无法运转
Just can't function no more
于是爱
And love
爱会将我们撕裂
Love will tear us apart
一次又一次
Again
爱
Love
爱会将我们撕裂
Love will tear us apart
一次又一次
Again
于是爱会将我们撕裂一次又一次
And love
爱会将我们撕裂
Love will tear us apart
一次又一次
Again